as well as losses of stature. The numbers of stunted children under the age of five, in most regions of the world, has been declining. And I really hate to say this, but the only place where they haven't been declining is here, in Africa. Here, 59 million children, three in 10 in that age group, struggle to meet their genetic potential -- their full genetic potential. Protein is one of our most important dietary requirements, and evidence shows that lack of essential amino acids, the building blocks of proteins, in young children's diets, can result in stunting. Essential amino acids are called essential because we can't synthesize them in our bodies. We have to get them from our foods and the best sources are animal-derived: milk, meat and eggs. Most protein consumed on the African continent is crop-based. And although we have millions of smallholder farmers rearing animals, livestock production is not as easy as we think. The big livestock gaps between rich countries and poor countries are due to poor animal health. Endemic livestock diseases, some of them transmissible to humans, threaten not only livestock producers in those poor countries, but all human health across all countries. This is a global pathogens network. It shows the pathogens found across the world according to the Enhanced Infectious Diseases database. And it shows those pathogens that share hosts. In a nutshell, we share pathogens, and thus diseases, with the species we live closest to: our livestock. And we call these zoonotic diseases. Recent reports show that the deadly dozen zoonotic diseases kill 2.2 million people and sicken 2.4 billion people annually. And Jimmy says, "The greatest burden of zoonoses falls on one billion poor livestock keepers." We totally underestimate the importance of our smallholder farmers. We're beginning to recognize how important they are and how they influence our medical health, our biosafety and more recently, our cognitive and our physical health. They stand at the frontline of zoonotic epidemics. They pretty much underpin our existence. And they need to know so much, yet most lack knowledge on livestock disease prevention and treatment. So how do they learn? Apart from shared experiences,
así como también pérdidas de estatura. El número de niños menores de cinco años con retraso en el crecimiento en la mayoría de las regiones del mundo, ha ido disminuyendo. Y realmente odio decir esto, pero el único lugar donde no ha disminuido es aquí, en África. Aquí, 59 millones de niños, tres de cada 10 en ese grupo de edad, luchan para alcanzar su potencial genético, su potencial genético completo. La proteína es uno de nuestros requisitos dietéticos más importantes, y la evidencia muestra que la falta de aminoácidos esenciales, los bloques de construcción de proteínas, en las dietas de los niños pequeños, puede provocar retraso en el crecimiento. Los aminoácidos esenciales se llaman esenciales porque se pueden sintetizar en nuestros cuerpos. Y hay que obtenerlos de nuestros alimentos y las mejores fuentes son de origen animal: leche, carne y huevos. La mayoría de las proteínas que se consumen en el continente africano se basan en cultivos de cereal. Y aunque tenemos millones de pequeños agricultores criando animales, la producción ganadera no es tan fácil como creemos. Las grandes brechas ganaderas entre los países ricos y los pobres se deben a la mala salud de los animales. Enfermedades endémicas del ganado, algunas de ellas transmisibles a los humanos, amenazan no solo a los productores de ganado en esos países pobres, sino a toda la salud humana en todos los países. Esto es una red global de patógenos. Muestra los patógenos encontrados en todo el mundo de acuerdo con la base de datos mejorada de Enfermedades Infecciosas. Y muestra los patógenos que comparten huéspedes. En una palabra, compartimos patógenos, y por lo tanto enfermedades, con la especie que vivimos más cerca de: nuestro ganado Y llamamos a estas enfermedades zoonóticas. Los informes recientes muestran que la docena mortal de enfermedades zoonóticas mata a 2.2 millones de personas y enfermar a 2.4 billones de personas anualmente. Y Jimmy dice: "La mayor carga de zoonosis" recae en mil millones de ganaderos pobres". Subestimamos por completo la importancia de nuestros pequeños agricultores. Estamos comenzando a reconocer cuán importantes son y cómo influyen en nuestra salud médica, en nuestra bioseguridad y más recientemente, en nuestra salud cognitiva y salud física. Se encuentran en la primera línea de las epidemias zoonóticas. Ellos prácticamente sustentan nuestra existencia. Y ellos necesitan saber mucho, pero la mayoría carece de conocimiento sobre prevención y tratamiento de enfermedades del ganado. Y ¿cómo aprenden? Además de experiencias compartidas,
trial and error, conventional farming extension services are boots on the ground and radio -- expensive and hard to scale in the face of population growth. Sounds pretty gloomy, doesn't it? But we're at an interesting point in Africa. We're changing that narrative using innovative solutions, riding across scalable technologies. Knowledge doesn't have to be expensive. My company developed an agricultural platform called iCow. We teach farmers best livestock practices using SMS
prueba y error, los servicios agrícolas convencionales son botas en el suelo y radio. Algo costoso y difícil de escalar frente al crecimiento de la población. Suena bastante sombrío, ¿no? Pero estamos en un punto interesante en África. Estamos cambiando esa narrativa usando soluciones innovadoras, manejando tecnologías escalables. El conocimiento no tiene que ser costoso. Mi compañía desarrolló una plataforma agrícola llamada iCow. Enseñamos a los agricultores a mejorar prácticas ganaderas usando SMS
over simple, low-end phones. Farmers receive three SMSs a week on best livestock practices, and those that execute the messages go on to see increases in productivity within as short a time as three months. The first increases in productivity, of course, are improved animal health.
con teléfonos sencillos de gama baja. Los agricultores reciben tres SMS por semana con las mejores prácticas ganaderas, y aquellos que las implementan, ven incrementos en la productividad en un corto tiempo como tres meses. Los primeros aumentos en la productividad son la mejora de la salud animal.
We use SMS because it is retentive. Farmers store their messages, they write them down in books, and in effect,
Usamos SMS porque es retentivo. Los agricultores almacenan sus mensajes, los escriben en libros, y en efecto,
we're drip-feeding agricultural manuals into the fields. We recognize that we are all part of the global food network: producers and consumers, you and me, and every farmer. We're focusing now on trying to bring together producers and consumers to take action and take responsibility for not only food security, but for food safety. This beautiful animal is an African-Asian Sahiwal crossed with a Dutch Fleckvieh. She's milkier than her Sahiwal mom, and she's sturdier and more resistant to disease than her Fleckvieh father.
estamos entregando manuales agrícolas a los campos. Reconocemos que todos somos parte de la red mundial de alimentos: productores y consumidores, usted y yo, y cada agricultor. Nos estamos centrando ahora en tratar de unir a productores y consumidores para asumir la responsabilidad no solo de la seguridad alimentaria, sino de seguridad alimentaria Este animal es un cebú africano-asiático cruzado con un Fleckvieh holandés. Ella es más lechera que su madre cebú, y es más robusta y resistente a las enfermedades que su padre Fleckvieh.
In Ethiopia and Tanzania, the African Dairy Genetic Gains program is using SMS and cutting-edge genomics and pioneering Africa's first tropically adapted dairy breeding centers and dairy performance recording centers. Farmers contribute their production data -- milking records, breeding records and feeding records -- to the ADGG platform. This stage is synthesized through algorithms from some of the top livestock institutions in the world before it lands back in the farmers' hands in actionable SMSs. Customized data, customized responses all aimed at increasing productivity based on the potential on the ground. We're at a very interesting place in agriculture in Africa. By the end of this year, we'll have almost one billion mobile phone subscriptions. We have the power in our hands to ensure that livestock production systems are not only healthy, productive and profitable, but that farmers are knowledgeable, and more importantly, that our farmers are safe. Working with smallholder farmers is one of the best ways to guarantee food security. Working with smallholder farmers is one of the best ways to guarantee each and every child their full opportunity and ability to reach their full genetic potential. And harnessing the power of millions of smallholder farmers and their badass cows like mine,
En Etiopía y Tanzania, el programa African Dairy Genetic Gains usa SMS y genómica de vanguardia y son pioneros en los primeros centros de reproducción láctea adaptados en África y centros de registro de producción de productos lácteos. Los agricultores contribuyen con sus datos de producción: registros de ordeño, registros de cría y de alimentación a la plataforma ADGG. Esto se sintetiza mediante algoritmos de algunas de las mejores instituciones ganaderas del mundo antes de que vuelva a manos de los agricultores en SMS procesables. Datos personalizados, respuestas personalizadas todo apunta a aumentar la productividad basado en el potencial sobre el terreno. Estamos en un lugar muy interesante en la agricultura en África. Al final de este año, tendremos casi mil millones de suscripciones de telefonía móvil. Tenemos el poder en nuestras manos para que los sistemas de producción ganadera no solo sean saludables, productivos y rentables, sino para que los agricultores estén bien informados. Y más importante aún, para que nuestros agricultores estén a salvo. Trabajando con pequeños agricultores es una de la mejor forma de garantizar la seguridad alimentaria. Trabajar con los pequeños agricultores es una de la mejor manera de garantizar a cada niño su oportunidad completa y la capacidad de alcanzar su potencial genético completo. Y aprovechando el poder de millones de pequeños agricultores y sus tremendas vacas como la mía,
we should be able to bring a halt to stunting in Africa. Thank you. (Applause)
deberíamos ser capaces de detener el retraso del crecimiento en África. Gracias. (Aplausos)